<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Buckler on Mark Buckler</title>
    <link>http://markbuckler.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mark Buckler on Mark Buckler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 Mark Buckler</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a DJ Mix</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/me-djing3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me DJing at a local show&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the third in a series of three posts teaching you how to DJ!&lt;br /&gt;
Part 1: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/what-you-need-djing&#34;&gt;What You Need to Start DJing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 2: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics&#34;&gt;How to Learn DJ Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 3: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix&#34;&gt;How to Make a DJ Mix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, you&amp;rsquo;ve got your gear and you&amp;rsquo;ve practiced a few transitions. Now is the
time to dig into the meat of DJing: creating your mix. Below I describe my
personal method, but as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before there are many ways to succeed. If
you want to use Traktor instead of Rekordbox, ignore cue points completely,
never organize your music, or anything else go ahead! Just make sure that you&amp;rsquo;re
having fun and that you like the sound of your mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you get stuck at any point that&amp;rsquo;s OK! There are often ways to make
things easier for yourself. For example, I often recommend that new DJs practice
on House music since the clear repetitive beat is great for learning beat
matching and the long intros and outros make mixing a bit easier. As another
example, lets say you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to find songs with the right key and BPM. No
worries! You can search around for more tracks on Beatport to expand your
library, giving yourself more options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, lets get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions-for-how-to-make-a-dj-mix&#34;&gt;Instructions for how to make a DJ mix!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to and label new music you&amp;rsquo;ve added recently&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have an insanely good memory and can easily remember what songs
they want to play for any given mood or genre. I am not that kind of person! For
me, I find it very helpful to do a few small things whenever I load in new music
that help me down the line. When creating a new mix or playing live I am often
interested in finding tracks which fit a certain mood, are a certain genre, or
even just only showing my absolute favorite tracks. While BPM and key are easy
to filter by since they are automatically analyzed by Rekordbox, there is no
feature for analyzing mood, genre, or your personal taste. This is where
labeling and Rekordbox intelligent playlists come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I add new music into my library I will first analyze the tracks to
get BPM and key, but then I will label each track. By labeling I mean that in
Rekordbox I add labels in brackets in the comments of each track which describe
the genre, mood, and anything else I might want to sort by later. I also rate
the track from 0-5 stars. As an example, in the comments of one of my favorite
songs called &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/ophelia_records/caster-ironheart-kingslayer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kingslayer by Caster &amp;amp;
Ironheart&lt;/a&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve written: &amp;ldquo;[Dubstep], [Epic], [Orchestral]&amp;rdquo; and I&amp;rsquo;ve rated it 5 stars.
When labeling a song I try to have at least one label for genre and mood
respectively. Feel free to use whatever labels make sense for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conveniently view all songs that you&amp;rsquo;ve labeled by any given mood or
genre, you can create &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rBCIzg-84xM&amp;amp;ab_channel=DirtySecretz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;intelligent
playlists&lt;/a&gt;
in Rekordbox. Each new intelligent playlist you create will pull songs from your
entire collection based on a few rules that you set. For example, I have an
intelligent playlist labeled Dubstep which includes all tracks that contain the
text &amp;ldquo;[Dubstep]&amp;rdquo; in their comments. This means that every time I add a new
track and label it as Dubstep, it will automatically be added to this playlist.
I&amp;rsquo;ve set up intelligent playlists for all of my favorite genres and moods,
making it very easy for me to find what I need!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decide on what you&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish with this mix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answers to the questions below should inform all other decisions you make in
the rest of planning out your mix. Here your goal is to decide on what you are
trying to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What experience would you like your audience to have? What is the general
vibe you&amp;rsquo;re going for? Do you want people on the dance floor to just nod
slightly, sway, shuffle, headbang, mosh, break the rail, etc? Is this a
promotional recording? If so, what kinds of songs and transitions would the
reviewer be looking for?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will this set be in-person, on a livestream, or just Soundcloud? If live,
consider what the DJs before and after you will be playing. Are you an
opener or headliner? If on a livestream, give yourself opportunities in the mix
to respond to comments, or be prepared to change what you play based on requests
that come in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What DJ skills would you like to use? If this is your first mix, maybe
you&amp;rsquo;ll rely on simple fades. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been playing for a while, try to
come up with a challenge or goal. Would you like to do mashups, use more of your
controller&amp;rsquo;s performance features, use drop swaps, or mix genres in ambitious
ways?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How long should the mix be? Standard set times include 15, 30, or 60
minutes. If you&amp;rsquo;re playing live then timing is very important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select your signpost songs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is arguably the most important step of all: deciding on your main
tracks. Consider all of the answers you gave to the questions above when making
these decisions. Here the goal isn&amp;rsquo;t to choose all of the songs you will play,
but instead to choose songs that you think are especially good. In the next step
you will add songs to glue these together. I&amp;rsquo;ve provided a few suggestions below
for guidance on how to select songs. To start, make a new Rekordbox playlist for
your mix, and add tracks to the playlist when you decide you&amp;rsquo;d like to play
them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For your first track, choose a song that has an interesting introduction.
Look for something dramatic and slow building. Avoid a song with extremely
high energy or one that starts with a boring drum loop. If none of the tracks
you&amp;rsquo;d like to play have interesting introductions, consider making it your own
by adding in some kind of voice-over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For your last track, be especially concious of who will be playing after
you. If you are playing as support for a headlining DJ, consider slowly
bringing down the energy a little bit at the end to give the crowd time to
recover. If you are the headliner, try to have something really fun saved for
the end like a new song you&amp;rsquo;ve made or at least an especially epic track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the tracks in between, there are many reasons to choose a
specific song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Songs that define the vibe you&amp;rsquo;re going for&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Songs that you&amp;rsquo;ve recently added to your collection or are especially
excited about&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Songs that you think the audience will get excited by (classics, brand new
music, EDM remixes of non-EDM songs)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Songs you&amp;rsquo;ve produced&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Songs that you&amp;rsquo;ve identified are good for mashups or can be used to
play with performance features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add some breaks in the action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, choosing the songs to play in a mix is like a combination between
writing a story and building a puzzle. Just like when writing a story, your goal
should be to intentionally raise and lower tension by playing songs with certain
energy levels at certain times. There are a few different ways to think about
structuring a story, but I think the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.reedsy.com/guide/story-structure/three-act-structure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;three act
structure&lt;/a&gt;
is especially helpful for this analogy. As you can see in the image below, each
of the story&amp;rsquo;s three acts consist of rising tension and then releasing tension.
Each subsequent act builds tension higher than the previous, resulting in a very
captivating story. When selecting signpost songs most people immediately
gravitate to the most exciting or highest energy songs they want to play, so now
is the time to add in a few lower energy songs. Make sure that the new songs
still fit your vibe but will help you lower the tension. Giving your audience
time to recover in-between increasingly intense climaxes will make for an
amazing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/three-act-structure.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Three act structure&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add any puzzle pieces you might be missing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the analogies of the story and the puzzle? Well now lets talk about
the puzzle. At the end of the day, it is always technically possible to
transition from one track to any other track, but not all transitions are
created equal. Large changes in key, BPM, or genre might force you to use a
simple &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/tb5hlwCWdiQ?t=358&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;echo out and then press play&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;
transition which can take your audience out of the experience if used too
frequently. Personally, I like to use as many smooth transitions as possible in
my mixes while still giving myself the option to use a few harsher transitions
if it fits the mood. To give myself more opportunities to discover great smooth
transitions (when practicing in the next few steps), I take this time to add a
few extra tracks to the list which bridge gaps in BPM and key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, lets say that you have a song that you&amp;rsquo;d really like to play
with a BPM/key of 120/7A and another song with a BPM/key of 128/9A. To make this
transition easier, add a few songs in-between these tracks which have BPMs of
120-128 and keys of 7A, 8A, and 9A. Its sometimes hard to know which songs will
have great points for transitioning before practicing, so give yourself a few
options before eventually cutting down the total number of songs in later steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/rekordbox_related_tracks.png&#34; alt=&#34;Related tracks window&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make this step easier, Rekordbox has an awesome feature called &amp;ldquo;related
tracks&amp;rdquo; (highlighted in green in the image above). A helpful tutorial on related
tracks can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z2ctw3kmC2c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and
there quite a few different ways to use the feature, but the most common way is
to search your entire collection and filter for tracks within a certain BPM
range and key range around a track of your choice. This is really great and can
often dramatically simplify the act of finding the right track for the right
place in your mix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adjust the beat grid and add cue points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as not everyone labels their music, not everyone uses cue points. For
folks with great memory there is no need, but for me I find cue points to be an
especially valuable tool. Adding cue points can take a bit of time and it
doesn&amp;rsquo;t help with sorting music, so while I have labeled all of the tracks in my
collection I&amp;rsquo;ll only add cue points to tracks that I think I might play in my
next mix. So, once you&amp;rsquo;ve got a list of tracks you&amp;rsquo;d like to practice
transitions on lets get to setting cue points!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary goal when setting cue points is to put visual indicators on
specific parts of the song which you think would lend themselves well to
transitioning. If both of the two songs you&amp;rsquo;re transitioning between have lots
of complexity (intense synths, drums, or vocals) then the listener will feel
overwhelmed if you fade between them. Thankfully, as you learned earlier, songs
are constructed from phrases (typically with a standard 8 bar length) which each
have certain properties. While every song is different, it is typical for songs
to have most of their complexity reserved to the drop or chorus of the song,
which leaves other phrases like the introduction, buildup, breakdown, and outro
as good potential opportunities for fading between songs. So, lets identify
where these phrases are in the song and then set our cue points!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the image below I&amp;rsquo;ve shown what a track looks like when its filled out
with all of the cue points I use in my system (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8MlYWO9BNM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phil Harris&amp;rsquo;
system&lt;/a&gt;). Each cue point is color
coded as well which helps me immediately remember what the points mean even if I
haven&amp;rsquo;t listened to the song in a long time. The orange cue point is for the
start of the song and the green cue point is for the start of the first drop.
Each red cue point represents the start of an 8 bar phrase which I expect to be
especially good for transitioning (either into or out of this song). When
choosing which 8 bar phrases to put a red cue point on, I&amp;rsquo;ll typically start
with 8 bars before the first drop, 8 bars before the end of the song, and then
the least complex 8 bars in-between the first and the second drop. Each blue cue
point is simply 8 bars before the upcoming red cue point. When transitioning
between tracks with this system I&amp;rsquo;ll typically set up the new track to start at
a blue cue point, and then press play when the blue cue points on each track are
aligned. This gives me 8 bars of extra time to beatmatch in-between pressing
play and fading in the next track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/rekordbox_cue_points.png&#34; alt=&#34;Assigning cue points&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start setting your own cue points, put your Rekordbox in export mode and
set your beat jump value to be 8 bars. I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn a light blue box in the image
below to highlight where you can set your beat jump. The arrows in the light
blue box can be clicked to jump forward or back in the track by the amount of
time shown below. Ok, now set each cue point one by one! I&amp;rsquo;ve written it out in
a few convenient steps below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the start of the drop. This is a great place to start since the start
of the drop is the easiest place to check if your beat grid is aligned
properly or not. You should see that just like the image above, the start of the
drop should be aligned with the red arrows on the beat grid, which indicate the
start of each bar. If this isn&amp;rsquo;t true, you can click on grid (highlighted by the
pink box in the image above) to adjust the grid placement. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve verified
your grid is aligned, place a green cue point on D (by clicking on D as shown in
the red box) at the start of the first drop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jump back by 8 bars (left arrow in light blue box) and place a red cue
point in C. You can change the color of cue points by right clicking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jump back another 8 bars and set a blue cue point on B.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For cue point A, place an orange cue point at the start of the first
measure of the song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to the end of the last bar of the song. Jump back 8 bars and place a
red cue point in H.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jump back another 8 bars and place a blue cue point in G.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the simplest 8 bars in-between the two (or more) drops. Place a red
cue point in F at the start of this 8 bars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jump back 8 bars and place a blue cue point in E.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Export your playlist to USB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use CDJs or an all-in-one DJ system, export your playlist to USB so you
can load you music. For a video explaining how, take a look
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1sGxfi--y2I&amp;amp;ab_channel=Crossfader&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re on Windows, you
may find &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/316977/how-to-format-usb-drives-larger-than-32gb-with-fat32-on-windows/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
guide&lt;/a&gt;
helpful as you&amp;rsquo;ll need FAT32 format but will likely have a USB which is larger than 32 GB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiment with transitions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need a DJ controller for this step. Start going down your set list
and experiment with fade transitions, drop swaps, and all kinds of different
transitions to see what you like best. Feel free to get creative! Use loops to
extend certain parts of the song for easier transitioning, or fill empty space
within the transition with noise effects. Have some fun with it! You can keep
track of what transitions you like with a notepad or spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finalize your set list and transitions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have groups of songs that you really like the transitions between,
you can combine these groups and create your final set list! Remember that you
will want to tell your story with building and releasing tension, so keep this
in mind when making your final decisions. Also, your total set time will need to
match whatever you set out to have as your goal, so make sure to practice your
full set from beginning to end to know your total set time. You may need to
remove or add songs to get to the right time. Lastly, if you are playing live on
a different set of hardware (for example CDJs) you will need to make sure that
your cue points will work with that hardware. For example, some old CDJs only
allow 3 cue points, so you will need to remove additional cue points before
exporting if you want them to show up. Thankfully you really only need 2 (one
for when you transition in and one when you transition out). I still like
starting with more cue points though since it gives you many
options when finding your favorite transition between tracks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Play and/or record your mix!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to perform. Enjoy the ride! If the
audience sees that you are having fun, then they will feel like they can have
fun with it too :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all there is to it! Thank you for reading, I hope you found this helpful.
If you have any questions then feel free to add them below, and if you&amp;rsquo;d like to
hear some of the mixes that I&amp;rsquo;ve made you can check out my Soundcloud profile
&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/quoththeraver&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;at this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn DJ Basics</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/me-djing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me DJing at a local show&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second in a series of three posts teaching you how to DJ!&lt;br /&gt;
Part 1: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/what-you-need-djing&#34;&gt;What You Need to Start DJing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 2: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics&#34;&gt;How to Learn DJ Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 3: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix&#34;&gt;How to Make a DJ Mix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great, you&amp;rsquo;ve got your musical knowledge, DJ software &amp;amp; hardware, and your music
library. Lets get started on learning the fundamentals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-time-setup&#34;&gt;First time setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Import your music library into your DJ software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first step is to get your music library into your Rekordbox collection.
You will also want to analyze all of your songs to get their BPM and key
signature. To do this, simply click and drag songs into the Rekordbox window. If
they don&amp;rsquo;t begin analyzing automatically, you can select them and then select
analyze tracks when right clicking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend changing a few settings in Rekordbox. For example, I
recommend you set your column headers to be the following: Preview, Artwork,
Track Title, Artist, BPM, Key, Rating, and Comments. You can choose whatever
columns you want displayed by right clicking on the header of your collection
display window. I also recommend setting the waveform display to be RGB (this
makes it easier to identify phrases in the waveform) and the key display to be
Camelot notation (this makes it easier to check if tracks are in key). Both of
these modes can be changed in the Rekordbox settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Set up and familiarize yourself with your hardware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hook up your DJ controller to your laptop, some speakers, and a pair of
headphones. Because this is your first time DJing, you might not be familiar
with all of the different buttons and knobs on your controller. The video below
is a great explanation of how to use the DDJ-400 controller. The DDJ-400 is my
recommendation for a good beginner controller, but even if you have different
hardware the video will still be helpful since it goes over all the basics which
are included on all DJ hardware. Once you watch that video, you will have a much
better idea of how to use your new equipment!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_gktzXnZVJk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-skills-to-learn&#34;&gt;Basic skills to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice beat matching by ear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When transitioning between two tracks, it is important that the beats of the
two songs are synchronized (matched). When playing two tracks on a controller or
all-in-one DJ system you can visually see if the beats are aligned or not. To be
honest, using this visual cue to beat match is how I got started, but it does
have some issues. The problem comes in if the beat grid of one of the songs has
been analyzed incorrectly, or if you are using CDJs (which display song
waveforms separately without being on top of each other). For this reason it is
important for all new DJs to learn how to beat match by ear. For an excellent
explanation and demonstration of beat matching by ear I recommend the video
below.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/GuE5x65XZF4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice transitioning between songs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have your music library in your DJ software, you&amp;rsquo;ve set up your
hardware, familiarized yourself with its knobs, and you&amp;rsquo;ve practiced beat
matching by ear, you&amp;rsquo;re finally ready to do your first transition! Start by
finding a House track which has an intro and outro which consists almost
entirely of just a simple drum beat (this keeps it simple). Then, add this track
to both of your decks and practice transitioning from the outro of the song on
one track into the outro of the song on the other track. Transitions are much
better demonstrated than explained, so take a look at the video below to learn
more.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Y4dqD-g7SHE?start=1545?&#34;
  style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you feel more comfortable with the basic fade, try transitioning
between two different songs with similar BPM and key. Once you feel comfortable
with BPM adjustment, beat matching, EQs and fading, you&amp;rsquo;re off to the races!
There are many other types of transitions of course (and feel free to create
your own!), but for EDM DJs the basic fade can get you nearly all of the way
there. For more creative transition ideas check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Hc8bmEaCqM&amp;amp;ab_channel=Crossfader&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
video&lt;/a&gt;, and
for examples of how to transition between two songs with significantly different
BPMs or genres, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-yuKamRvQOc&amp;amp;ab_channel=Crossfader&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, now that you know how to use your DJ controller and have practiced a
few different transitions, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to move on to making your first mix! For
some guidance on how to do that, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix&#34;&gt;my next blog
post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You Need to Start DJing</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/what-you-need-djing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/what-you-need-djing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/me-djing2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me DJing at a local show&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome! If you want to learn how to DJ, then you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. This is
the first in a series of three posts teaching you how to go from knowing nothing
to being able to play at your first party. Below I share a few personal details
about how I got started, but feel free to skip to &amp;ldquo;What you need to get started&amp;rdquo;
if you just want technical details. I hope you enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 1: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/what-you-need-djing&#34;&gt;What You Need to Start DJing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 2: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics&#34;&gt;How to Learn DJ Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Part 3: &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/how-to-mix&#34;&gt;How to Make a DJ Mix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-got-started-djing&#34;&gt;How I got started DJing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who know me well know that I have been a massive fan of electronic
dance music (aka EDM) ever since I first found it in 2008. I always loved the
energy and excitement of guitar solos in rock and metal, and I soon realized
that I could find that same energy and excitement but for the entirety of a song
in electronic music. Starting on Tiesto and Daft Punk got me hooked on Trance
and House, and I soon found a home in the Electro, Dubstep, and Drum &amp;amp; Bass
communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What some of you might not know is that from 2010 to 2012 I actually ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://quoththeraverarchive.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my own
EDM blog&lt;/a&gt;. While admittedly the
writing quality is a bit amateurish, I remember having a huge amount of fun
spending time digging around for new music and sharing it with curious friends. By
2012 the music of Skrillex and others had become so mainstream though that fewer
and fewer people were asking me for suggestions, and so I chose to end the blog.
Speaking of Skrillex, I actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://quoththeraverarchive.wordpress.com/2010/08/03/week-of-electro-part-3-skrillex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;posted about
him&lt;/a&gt;
way back in 2010 before he released his eventually Grammy-winning and massively
influential EP Scary Monsters and Nice Sprites. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know,
Skrillex&amp;rsquo;s earlier EDM production was a lot more electro focused, so back then I
chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O3Q7LtUGfUg&amp;amp;ab_channel=SkrillexFullHD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Slats Slats
Slats&lt;/a&gt; as
my favorite track by him. I still love that track, so much so that I played it
in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/quoththeraver/sawtooth-soiree-set&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sawtooth Soiree rave
mix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since ending my blog I had a dream of DJing and producing my own music, but
getting a bachelors, masters, and PhD in engineering took up all of my time. Now
that I finally have my weekends back, I&amp;rsquo;ve been diving deep into DJing and music
production. While I am still relatively new to music production, I am thrilled
to say that I have now successfully DJed more than a few raves and parties. You
can find recordings of my favorite mixes on &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/quoththeraver&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my Soundcloud
profile&lt;/a&gt;. When I told folks that I was
teaching &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/rebecca-smith-186&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my wife&lt;/a&gt; how to DJ, a few
other people expressed interest in learning. So, I&amp;rsquo;ve written these blog posts
to serve as a  reference for anyone who might like to learn. I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what I&amp;rsquo;ve written here, feel free to write them
in the comments below! Also, these are only my thoughts and systems for DJing.
There are many other ways to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-get-started&#34;&gt;What you need to get started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, thats enough of me telling my life story before sharing the recipe! Let&amp;rsquo;s
start with what you will need before you can get started. Specifically, some
musical knowledge, a music library, DJ software, and DJ hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Musical Knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you&amp;rsquo;ll need before you get started on DJing is some
knowledge of music theory. The act of making a smooth transition between tracks is core
to DJing, and these smooth transitions are only possible due to patterns that
are shared between different pieces of music. By learning what these patterns
are and what words to use to describe them you will become a much better DJ. If
you aren&amp;rsquo;t classically trained in music, the five most important new vocabulary
words you will need to learn are beats, bars, phrases, BPM, and key signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beats, bars, and phrases are each a different level of hierarchy in the
structure of music. Each song is made up of multiple phrases
(introduction, breakdown, drop, bridge, etc), each phrase is made up of multiple
bars (typically 8 bars in EDM), and each bar is made up of multiple beats
(typically 4 beats in EDM). When transitioning from one track to another it is
helpful to keep phrasing in mind since overlapping certain phrases tends to
sound better than others. For great examples and a deep explanation, check out
the video below by my red-headed brother from another mother &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCv5TGu1jwiqWhzw9wj01mIQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phil
Harris&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/ZqGUt1U8gPo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BPM stands for Beats Per Minute, so it is a measurement of the speed of a
given song. When we transition between songs we typically want each of
these songs to be playing at the same speed and for the beats to be aligned. In
engineering terminology we would say that we want both the frequency and the
phase of the songs to be the same. By using a DJ controller we can adjust the
frequency (BPM) of a song by adjusting the tempo slider, and we can adjust the
phase (alignment in time) by spinning the side of the jog wheel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key signature of a given song corresponds to the specific set of notes
used to create that song. The easiest key signature to explain is C Major,
which includes just the white keys on a piano. Certain key signatures share a
lot of the same notes, and so you can predict how well two songs will sound
together if you know both of their key signatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/CamelotWheel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Camelot Wheel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it easier for people
to remember which key signatures share the most notes, the Camelot system (shown
in the image above) was created. On the Camelot wheel, each cell represents a
given key with a classical name (such as C Major) and a Camelot name (such as 8B
for C Major). The keys that are adjacent on the wheel  to any particular key
share the most amount of notes, and therefore will sound the best to mix
between. If you use Camelot notation you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to look at the wheel to
know which keys will sound good with any other given key, since all adjacent
cells either share a number with the key you&amp;rsquo;re interested in or they
increase/decrease the number of the key by one. For a great explanation of
mixing in key I recommend the video below by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCM4u0gp8gm99w9MXQ7ZI8Mw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Crossfader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/U_tS7iMwU54&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It is worth mentioning that Rekordbox does now support displaying keys
in Camelot notation, and also that it isn&amp;rsquo;t always necessary to strictly mix in
key. The ultimate test of whether or not a transition sounds good is if you
think it sounds good. Software tools do their best to identify what key a song
is in, but sometimes they can get it wrong. Also, depending on how the songs are
written it may be possible to jump by 2 cells instead of 1 on the Camelot wheel,
since those keys will only differ by 2 notes. A good rule of thumb worth
repeating is when DJing, always remember to trust your ears!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music Library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we live in an age when streaming is king, most people listen to music
through Spotify, Soundcloud, and Apple Music. Thankfully some DJ software
(including Rekordbox) does enable you to play music from &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; streaming
services, but this functionality requires that you bring a laptop and have a
good internet connection wherever you play. Most DJs prefer to work with actual
song files instead since that offers the most flexibility and reliability.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en-us/product/player/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer CDJs&lt;/a&gt; are industry
standard and can load music from a properly formatted USB, so most
DJs don&amp;rsquo;t need to bring anything other than a USB filled with their music files
when they go to play at a club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK cool, so if you want music files for DJing then how should you get
them? This is a legitimate question if you&amp;rsquo;ve become used to streaming.
Frustratingly, Spotify and the other streaming services purposefully make it
hard for you to buy music on their site since otherwise you would have less
of a need for them. The best way that I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far to buy songs from a
Spotify playlist is a web app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypem.com/merch-table&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Merch
Table&lt;/a&gt; which can convert a spotify playlist into
a convenient list of links to buy the songs on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;. If instead you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an iTunes-esque
website optimized for DJing then you should check out
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beatport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beatport&lt;/a&gt;. Beatport has a significant advantage over
iTunes for a few reasons, but the biggest thing for me is seeing the BPM and key
for every track (this will become important when you&amp;rsquo;re deciding which songs to
mix with others). Finally, there are DJ Pools which are monthly
subscriptions to services which enable you to download unlimited song files. For
more details and a recent review of the top DJ Pools, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://djtechreviews.com/audio-software/best-dj-pool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DJ Software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your music library, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to import it into your choice
of DJ software! DJ software will play a few important roles for you: music
library organization, track preparation for performance, and either exporting
your library to a USB or enabling a non-standalone DJ controller to play music.
There are quite a few options for DJ software, so if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure which to
choose then I recommend taking a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sweetwater.com/insync/which-dj-software-is-right-for-me/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
post&lt;/a&gt;
which describes the pros and cons of the top 3 platforms. My personal favorite
DJ software is &lt;a href=&#34;https://rekordbox.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rekordbox&lt;/a&gt; because of its excellent
organization and USB export tools, so the rest of this blog post will describe
how to make a mix using Rekordbox specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/rekordbox.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Rekordbox window&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DJ Hardware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your home DJ studio will consist of a few components: a DJ controller or
CDJs+mixer, speakers, headphones, and optionally a formatted USB stick. Most
people already have speakers, headphones, and USB sticks, so here I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly
go over the differences between DJ controllers, all-in-one DJ systems, and CDJs.
Each kind of DJ hardware has a different price point and different
functionality, but any of these types of hardware can be used to learn how to
DJ. Because &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en-us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer DJ&lt;/a&gt; is the standard in
most bars and clubs (and I also use Pioneer DJ hardware) all of the examples
given below are from Pioneer DJ, but hardware from other manufacturers like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.denondj.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Denon DJ&lt;/a&gt; can also work for you. Also, the costs that
I list are for new equipment, but it is often possible to find used equipment on
Facebook marketplace or even in stores like Guitar Center. Older versions of
this hardware are often available as well, so keep an eye out for those if
you&amp;rsquo;re trying to save money. Finally, if you would like to try out DJing before
spending money on hardware then you might be interested in one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.pointblankmusicschool.com/7-best-dj-apps-for-mixing-on-the-go/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;many DJ
apps&lt;/a&gt;
for tablets and phones. Personally, I would recommend a cheap controller instead
of an app since even the cheap controllers have a lot more in common with
standard hardware than apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DJ Controller ($150-$250)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a beginner then a DJ controller is right for you. This is the
cheapest DJ hardware available, and when combined with a laptop it can do
absolutely everything you need to practice DJing.  You will need a computer to
organize your music anyway, so there is no harm in needing a computer to play
music. Most controllers also have convenient performance pads mapped to cue
points which I find to be especially helpful. Effects and looping functionality
are nearly always available as well. The example I show below is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en-us/product/controller/ddj-400/gold/overview/#/color-picker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer
DDJ-400-N&lt;/a&gt;,
which is very similar to the controller that I started out with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/DDJ-400.png&#34; alt=&#34;DJ Controller&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All-in-one DJ System ($1,500-$2,000)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky enough to start DJing in clubs but don&amp;rsquo;t have a ridiculous
amount of money to spend on a full club system for your home studio, you may be
interested in an all-in-one DJ system. All-in-one DJ systems offer all of the
same functionality of a DJ controller but also offer a built-in screen for
viewing waveforms &amp;amp; browsing songs, balanced connections for connecting to
professional speakers/monitors, physically larger controls (easier to change
BPM), and don&amp;rsquo;t require a laptop. The layout of
all-in-one DJ systems is also very similar to the corresponding CDJs, which will
help you become familiar with that layout. Finally, all-in-one DJ systems work
by importing music from a USB (just like CDJs), so these systems are great for
big parties with multiple DJs since each new DJ only needs to connect their USB
to get started. The example I show below is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en/product/all-in-one-system/xdj-rx3/black/overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer
XDJ-RX2&lt;/a&gt;,
which is very similar to the system that I currently use at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/XDJ-RX3.png&#34; alt=&#34;DJ System&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CDJs and Mixer ($3,000-$7,000+)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most dance clubs that I am familiar with use CDJs and a mixer for their
DJ hardware. Clubs like to use CDJ + mixer setups because they are physically
more robust, they can have 4 or more audio sources (such as additional CDJs,
analog turntables, or instruments), and because individual CDJs or mixers can be
replaced without needing to replace the entire system. Before you dump $5k on a
few CDJs though you should be aware that they also have a lot of drawbacks!
Beyond being very expensive, CDJ + mixer setups don&amp;rsquo;t typically have performance
pads for cue points (sometimes limiting you to 3 cue points total), don&amp;rsquo;t enable
you to beatmatch by eye since each display only shows one track at a time, and
are physically huge which can be real problem for folks in small apartments. So
why would you as a bedroom DJ ever want CDJs and a mixer? The only real reason
to do this is so that you can practice on equipment that is similar or identical
to what you will be playing on live at a club. If you rely on many cue points
and beatmatching by eye while practicing then you might be caught totally off
guard when you&amp;rsquo;re asked to play without those nice tools. The example I show
below is a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en/product/player/cdj-3000/black/overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer
CDJ-3000s&lt;/a&gt;
and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pioneerdj.com/en-us/product/mixer/djm-900nxs2/black/overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pioneer DJM-900NXS2
mixer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/dj-post/DJM-900NXS2-and-CDJ-3000-pair.png&#34; alt=&#34;CDJs and Mixer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK great, now you know what you need to get started DJing! To learn how to take
your musical knowledge, music library, and DJ setup to the next level with DJ
basics, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/post/learn-djing-basics&#34;&gt;my next blog post&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Bad Deep Learning Hardware</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/bad-dnn-asic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/bad-dnn-asic/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve greatly enjoyed my time as a graduate research intern at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://deepscale.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DeepScale&lt;/a&gt; and so I was pleased when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forrestiandola.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Forrest
Iandola&lt;/a&gt; asked me to give a talk to his team on
deep learning hardware. To keep the talk from being a boring list of slides
recounting famous (but dry) neural network hardware papers, we decided to structure it
like one of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Patterson_(computer_scientist)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;David
Patterson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s
talks which describe &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.eecs.berkeley.edu/Pubs/TechRpts/2013/EECS-2013-123.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to
do&lt;/a&gt;. The
talk was well received, so I decided to reformat it into this blog post. This
post does assume some knowledge of DNN processing, but for those of you who are
new to the topic I also provide explanations for each piece of advice in spoiler
tags. If you want to learn more about DNN processing, I recommend this excellent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.09039&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;survey paper&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rle.mit.edu/eems/people/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vivienne
Sze&lt;/a&gt; and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact by the way: Forrest and I first met way back in 2007 when our
respective projects made it to the AAAS national high school science fair! The
project I made for that competition developed into &lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US8289363B2/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my first
patent&lt;/a&gt; and eventually &lt;a href=&#34;http://firebrandinnovations.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my
first company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, a few disclaimers. 1) While I have read and written many papers
on DNN hardware design, I have never built DNN hardware in a corporate context.
2) These are my personal opinions and don&amp;rsquo;t reflect those held by DeepScale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, lets make some awful hardware!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;guidelines-for-making-bad-dnn-hardware&#34;&gt;Guidelines for Making Bad DNN Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make One Chip To Rule Them All&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training and inference both need fast access to memory and high parallelism,
so they&amp;rsquo;re pretty much the same thing. This means you can make just one chip
while claiming that your system is highly optimized for all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    Users interested in training and users interested in inference often
have fundamentally different hardware needs. For example: hardware for training
is generally evaluated on its throughput above all else, while hardware for
inference is typically optimized for latency. Data locality can be different as
well since activations  must be stored for all layers when training but
activations can be discarded during inference. Finally, training hardware will
often need to support much higher precision than inference hardware
due to the need for gradient computation in training. So while some hardware
optimizations improve performance overall, many design decisions will end up
placing your hardware somewhere along a trade-off curve. Without a clear focus
for what your potential users need, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that what you&amp;rsquo;ve built isn&amp;rsquo;t
useful to anyone in particular.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All DNNs are CNNs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most famous DNN paper in recent memory is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/4824-imagenet-classification-with-deep-convolutional-neural-networks.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AlexNet&lt;/a&gt;.
From this we can conclude that absolutely all neural networks are convolutional
image classifiers. Optimize your system for &lt;code&gt;3x3&lt;/code&gt; (or better yet, &lt;code&gt;5x5&lt;/code&gt;!)
convolutions and then claim that your system is a generic neural network
accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    CNNs are far from the only kind of neural network. Despite their
popularity in the hardware research community, Google found that CNNs accounted
for &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.04760&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;only 5%&lt;/a&gt; of their total DNN workload. The
other big players
include &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multilayer_perceptron&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multi-Layer Perceptrons&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recurrent_neural_network&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Recurrent Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt; such as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_short-term_memory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Long Short-Term Memory&lt;/a&gt;
networks. If you plan on making a generic deep learning processor then
optimizing for only CNNs is a huge oversight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to point out however that not all hardware must aspire to be
purely generic. After all, part of the reason why the hardware
community has been so interested in CNNs is the many
interesting and effective ways to accelerate them. This includes
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1803.06312&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my own work&lt;/a&gt;! Also, while Google servers may
not run CNN inference frequently, vision-heavy applications like self driving cars and
augmented reality rely heavily on CNNs. So, rather than claiming that optimizing
for CNNs is always a bad idea, I simply want to point out that choosing to
specialize for CNN computation must be done intentionally.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hammer that DRAM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPUs are good at deep learning and have tiny caches, so learn from this by
saving precious area for logic instead of on-chip memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    Good computer architects must always be thinking about the spatial and
temporal locality of data in their applications of choice. While many GPU
applications don&amp;rsquo;t have significant temporal locality (hence the reason for
small on-chip memory) this is certainly not the case for deep learning
workloads. As &lt;a href=&#34;https://stanford.edu/~songhan/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Song Han&lt;/a&gt; and others point out in
their paper on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1602.01528.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Efficient Inference
Engine&lt;/a&gt;: even without changing the
underlying computation, huge amounts of energy and time can be saved by simply
keeping network activations and model parameters on chip.
The &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1807.11164.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ShuffleNet V2&lt;/a&gt; paper also has some
excellent discussion about how memory hierarchy and memory access patterns
impact network performance.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All DNN Computation is Regular&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Literally all DNN computation is dense matrix multiplication. The regularity
and predictability of this computation means that we can always assume
maximum DRAM bandwidth and there&amp;rsquo;s no need for any hardware or software support
for load balancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    As it turns out, lots of DNN computation can be irregular and load
balancing can be a hard problem even with fully regular computation. Irregular
DNN computation be a result of &lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/openai-assets/blocksparse/blocksparsepaper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;leveraging
sparsity&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1510.00149&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;model compression&lt;/a&gt;, or a variety of other
techniques. Load balancing issues can come from this irregular computation, but
can also come from general scheduling challenges when using systolic arrays
like those in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1704.04760.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TPU&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://people.csail.mit.edu/emer/papers/2016.06.isca.eyeriss_architecture.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eyeriss&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NoM NoM NoM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly the fact that the NoM (Network of the Moment) is so popular now
means that it will always be popular. Ensure that your hardware gets the
most users by fully optimizing your chip for the NoM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    One of the most fundamental concepts in computer architecture is the
specialization-generalization trade-off. The fully specialized side of this trade-off
would be to take a single algorithm and bake it directly into hardware. This
dramatically improves computational efficiency, but optimizing hardware for a
single algorithm means that the resulting hardware can&amp;rsquo;t do anything other than
compute that algorithm. So, optimizing your hardware for the network of the
moment is a dangerous proposition considering the deluge of papers every year
from NIPS, ICML, ICCV, and CVPR. As an example consider the evolution from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.nips.cc/paper/4824-imagenet-classification-with-deep-convolutional-neural-networks.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AlexNet&lt;/a&gt;,
to &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1512.03385&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ResNet&lt;/a&gt;, to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.07360&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SqueezeNet&lt;/a&gt;, to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.04861&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MobileNet&lt;/a&gt;. The software development cycle
(from idea to implementation) can be around 6 months, while the hardware
development cycle is often closer to 2 years. This means that
overspecialization can lead to your chip being obsolete before it&amp;rsquo;s even built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite issue can also come up if there is too much of a focus on
antiquated models. Computer architecture researchers in academia are especially
susceptible to this issue, but hardware companies can be too if they aren&amp;rsquo;t
careful. For more discussion on this take a look &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8259424&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;8 Bit Means 8 Bit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNNs are famously well suited for low precision computation, so we only need
to support 8 bit accumulations. Rather than telling anyone that this is what
your hardware does, hide it inside your proprietary DNN framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    Computing with 8 bit weights and activations for inference may be one
thing, but accumulating in 8 bits will lead to extreme overflow issues. To begin
with, multiplying two 8 bit numbers together results in a 16 bit product.
Additionally (pun totally intended), many products will be added together as a
part of the multiply accumulate chains inherent to matrix-matrix multiplication.
For this reason, hardware systems must accumulate with precision significantly
larger than that used to store activations and weights. For a more in-depth
discussion of the different kinds of precision and their importance in deep
neural networks I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.cornell.edu/~cdesa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris De Sa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s
paper on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5789782/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;low-precision
SGD&lt;/a&gt;, which includes
details focused on training which is an entirely different issue altogether.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Latency = 1 / Throughput&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latency is clearly the inverse of throughput, so only report frames per
second with large batch sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    Large batch sizes are often used to increase the temporal locality of
data when training. This significantly reduces the average time needed to
process each frame. For this reason supporting large batch sizes and reporting
performance when using large batch sizes can be completely reasonable. This is
not at all the case for applications which require real-time inference like self
driving cars and augmented reality however. For these applications, waiting to
group multiple frames into a batch is unacceptable since a result is expected
for each frame soon after being received. So, &amp;ldquo;average time per frame&amp;rdquo; is only
equal to real-time latency if the batch size is equal to 1. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/uploads/prod/2018/03/mi0218_Chung-2018Mar25.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project
Brainwave&lt;/a&gt;
paper has some great details on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This confusion between latency and
throughput is only one of many issues that can crop up when comparing the
metrics for one deep learning accelerator over the other. For more details, see
slide 20-25 of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rle.mit.edu/eems/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2018_cicc_forum.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;excellent
presentation&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avoid All Complexity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploiting &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.04485&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sparsity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.01528&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;model
compression&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.04760&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;systolic
arrays&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1803.06312&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;temporal
redundancy&lt;/a&gt; seems hard. Avoid all this hassle
by telling everyone that you&amp;rsquo;ll support these features but in the end just
do the bare minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    Choosing where your device falls on the specialization-generalization
trade-off curve is a critical decision. You&amp;rsquo;ve already chosen to build hardware
specifically for neural network computation, so go ahead and specialize! Without
any specific optimizations for your application of choice your system will be no
better than a general purpose CPU or GPU.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Yield Will Get Better, I Promise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device physics folks down the hall can surely scale their experimental
technology to production level soon. CMOS is old news. Its all about graphene,
spintronics, optical computing, or &amp;lt;insert your own post-CMOS tech here&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    This advice can go for pretty much any kind of computer architecture
research but is especially relevant for deep learning hardware due to its
popularity. Computer architects often get really excited when they find
themselves speaking with device physics people. New computing technologies sound
very promising and have all kinds of desirable properties. The challenge with
nearly all of these new technologies however is scaling the process from tens of
devices per chip to millions or billions of devices per chip. If you are a
process design engineer or a device physics person yourself then by all means do
research in that field, but if you are just a hardware engineer then be wary of
any technology that isn&amp;rsquo;t being used at an industrial scale. Otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll
find yourself putting bogus numbers in your architectural simulator and/or never
be able to fabricate your chip.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software? Lame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen, if we wanted to write software we would have joined Facebook. Let&amp;rsquo;s
just have one engineer extend gcc to compile to our instruction set so that we
aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; lying when we say that you can write code for our chip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Why is this so bad?&lt;/summary&gt;
    I hope this goes without saying, but hardware is useless without
software support! Hardware designers can get dismissive about software simply
because it isn&amp;rsquo;t their area of expertise but they really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. With a few
exceptions here and there, even application specific hardware must be
programmed. Any pitch for a new piece of hardware must include both the exciting
new features that the hardware provides as well as an in-depth description of
the software stack used to program the hardware. The features are why someone
might be interested in the hardware and the software stack is how someone might
use the hardware to leverage those great features. Because hardware designers
are the most comfortable with the complexities of their hardware, they should be
actively involved in the development of the software stack for their system.
&lt;/details&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps you develop a useless deep learning chip of your very own!
Did I miss any hardware design sins? If you can think of any, feel
free to let me know in the comments below. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Imaging Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/imaging-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/imaging-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compact talk describing the imaging pipeline from photons to pixels&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVA: Exploiting Temporal Redundancy in Live Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/isca2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/isca2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hardware support for deep convolutional neural networks (CNNs) is critical to advanced computer vision in mobile and embedded devices. Current designs, however, accelerate generic CNNs; they do not exploit the unique characteristics of real-time vision. We propose to use the temporal redundancy in natural video to avoid unnecessary computation on most frames. A new algorithm, activation motion compensation, detects changes in the visual input and incrementally updates a previously-computed output. The technique takes inspiration from video compression and applies well-known motion estimation techniques to adapt to visual changes. We use an adaptive key frame rate to control the trade-off between efficiency and vision quality as the input changes. We implement the technique in hardware as an extension to existing state-of-the-art CNN accelerator designs. The new unit reduces the average energy per frame by 54.2%, 61.7%, and 87.6% for three CNNs with less than 1% loss in vision accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVA: Exploiting Temporal Redundancy in Live Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/publication/isca2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 19:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/publication/isca2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patenting</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/patenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/patenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Useful information all about how to patent in both academia and industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Precision SqueezeDet</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/project/squeeze-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/project/squeeze-precision/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Invention Disclosures</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/idf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/idf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my post about
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patenting in academia and industry&lt;/a&gt;
then you know why you might want to file a patent with your university or
company. The first step to filing a patent in most organizations (after creating
the invention of course!) is filling out an Invention Disclosure Form or IDF.
These forms will be created, provided by, and reviewed by your organization&amp;rsquo;s
technology transfer office or center for technology licensing. While IDFs tend
to differ between organizations they are all intended as a way for the inventor
to communicate to the organization how a new invention works and why it is
worth patenting. If the result of the organization&amp;rsquo;s review is that the
invention should be patented then in-person meetings with patent attorneys will
be arranged to discuss in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is written as a guide for those of you who might be filling out your
first IDF. This may also be helpful to any of you who are creating the first
standard disclosure form for your organization. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some common
questions in IDFs and strategies for answering these questions well. As I say in
my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I am not a
patent attorney so please don&amp;rsquo;t take any of what I say here as legal advice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who are the inventors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases the answer to this question will be very straightforward.
Perhaps you were the only person on the project in which you created the
invention and you never discussed the invention with others. Most of the time,
however, people collaborate. If your invention was made in a project with other
people then the determination of who may or may not be considered an inventor is
a matter of discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;authorship&lt;/em&gt; on papers is generally given to people who have made
important contributions when building prototypes, performing testing, and
writing text for the paper, &lt;em&gt;inventorship&lt;/em&gt; is legally different. Patent law
defines an inventor of a patentable invention as someone who conceives of an
original, useful, and non-obvious idea. This can but does not necessarily
include students, professors, your boss, your employees, and other
collaborators. Use your best judgement and ask all collaborators who you believe
may have contributed to the idea considered in the invention disclosure. Only
after everyone agrees will the inventor list be settled. Keep in mind that who
gets to claim inventorship should not be based on charity, flattery, or spite.
Patents can and have been invalidated for an incorrect list of inventors. For
more information about this topic, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://otl.stanford.edu/documents/who_is_inv.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this helpful PDF&lt;/a&gt;
provided by Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Office of Technology Licensing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What problem does the invention solve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an invention to be useful and therefore worthy of patent protection, it
must solve some problem that exists in the world. If you are used to writing
research papers, you can think of this like the &lt;em&gt;motivation&lt;/em&gt; section in a
paper. Because the patent lawyers and other people reviewing this IDF won&amp;rsquo;t
necessarily be experts in your field make sure to include any scientific or
technical background that might be needed to understand why the invention is
useful and how it may work. This is similar to the &lt;em&gt;background&lt;/em&gt; section in a
paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What prior art are you aware of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prior art&amp;rdquo; simply refers to any patents, papers, documentation, or other
published information that you are aware of which is related to your invention.
This is similar to the &lt;em&gt;related work&lt;/em&gt; section in a research paper. If there is a
very large body of work in your field then try to focus on citing survey papers
for the general background and then limit your more specific citations to work
which is closely related. Also, do your best to list any other groups,
researchers, or companies who work in your area as it will help the attorneys
in their further prior art search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What competitors are you aware of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you list any competing products or inventions that you&amp;rsquo;re aware of.
Stress the flaws or drawbacks of each of your competitors so that you can more
easily demonstrate your advantage. If there aren&amp;rsquo;t yet any true solutions to the
problem that your invention solves then list any workarounds that you
might be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the unique features of the invention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you describe your invention&amp;rsquo;s competitive advantage and which
specific elements of your invention are novel. You can think about this like the
&lt;em&gt;contributions&lt;/em&gt; section in a paper. Try to focus both on why you are different
from the competition and why this difference results in a superior product or
method. Use your best sales skills!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the invention work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is often the most complex section of the IDF. Use pictures and visual
aids whenever possible. You could also consider including a glossary with
definitions of the jargon used throughout the IDF. Keep in mind that the readers
may not be as familiar with your subject area as you are. Technology offices try
to match inventions as closely to experts as possible, but some disciplines can
be very broad and others very specialized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there any alternative versions of the invention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In engineering we often need to make design decisions to optimize the
performance of our design or simplify the design process. Your final prototype
represents only one possible choice for each design decision. To prevent someone
from designing around your patent by making an insignificantly different choice
in their design, your patent attorney will try to make the claims of your patent
as general as possible. You can help your attorney by describing not just the
specifics of your tested prototype, but also the entire possible design space.
This can include variations that you haven&amp;rsquo;t tested, or even variations that you
have tested and have determined to be inferior to your final prototype.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How could the invention be used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you lay out all possible use cases for your invention. Ease of use is
important in evaluating the value of a potential patent. Overly onerous
inventions may not be worth the benefit they provide. If possible, provide
examples of other products or inventions with similar use cases. In a similar
spirit to listing alternative versions of your invention, get creative and try
to think of alternative uses for your invention as well. Alternative uses for
your work may make it more valuable and enable broader claims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can the use of this invention be detected?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discuss in my post on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patenting in academia and industry&lt;/a&gt;,
part of a patent&amp;rsquo;s value is how easy it is to detect when the invention is
being used without permission. Without the ability to detect the use of the
invention, the patent can&amp;rsquo;t be enforced and is therefore useless. Your patent
attorney may be more familiar with common methods for detecting use in your
field since this isn&amp;rsquo;t a common thought for researchers, but list whatever
methods you are aware of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who might want to purchase or license the potential patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is most relevant in academia where the assumption is not that
the patent will be used directly by your organization. Universities don&amp;rsquo;t make
products, and so a patent only has value if there is a demand for it! To answer
this question list any people or organizations who might be interested in buying
or licensing the potential patent from your organization. This can include the
most prominent companies in your field as well as any any startups you may be
aware of. Some technology offices may even begin marketing your idea before
deciding to patent your invention as a way of determining demand, so give them
as much help as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in a university and hope to launch a company using this patent,
be extremely up front about your goals. You may even want to contact the
technology licencing office before submitting an IDF to explain your intentions.
Without knowing your goals the technology licencing office may sell the patent
to an outside party without ever consulting you. Even simply marketing your
invention before it has been patented may prevent you from creating a stealth
mode startup. Make sure to communicate often and effectively with your
university&amp;rsquo;s office to avoid such an issue. Your business plan may be a part of
convincing the office to license to you instead of a large company, so prepare
your business plan as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After answering these 10 questions you will have successfully filled out your
first IDF. Congratulations!  As you can see, a great deal of the questions asked
in an IDF are similar to material that you may have already prepared for a
technical report or research publication. Feel free to directly copy and paste
from previous writing that you&amp;rsquo;ve done, and attach the original document to your
IDF for ease of reading. With any luck your organization will be interested in
filing a patent on your invention. May lots of patent filing bonuses or
licencing revenue flow your way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patenting in Academia and Industry</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/patenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/patenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all get excited about doing scientific or engineering research for different
reasons, but most of us seek the thrill of creating something entirely new.
In this way, research can be just as wonderful as the creative arts. Publishing
your new ideas is great for sharing information with the world, but sometimes
you want to sell your ideas too. This is where filing for a patent can be very
useful. I have some experience in this area as I have patented inventions
&lt;a href=&#34;http://patents.google.com/patent/US8289363B2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on my own&lt;/a&gt;,
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US9344099B2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;industry&lt;/a&gt;,
and most recently in academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I can&amp;rsquo;t cover the entire topic of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intellectual_property&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Intellectual Property (IP) law&lt;/a&gt;
in a single blog post, I will choose instead to answer questions that someone
might have if they were interested in patenting at a company or university. I
hope other researchers and inventors like myself will find this information
useful. Also, I am not a patent attorney, so please don&amp;rsquo;t take anything that I
say here as legal advice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t already know, a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patent&lt;/a&gt; on a specific idea gives
exclusive usage rights of that idea to whoever holds the patent. In theory, this
means that the patent holder can prevent others from using the idea. The person
who creates the invention is referred to as the &lt;em&gt;inventor&lt;/em&gt;, and the person or
organization who holds the patent is the &lt;em&gt;assignee&lt;/em&gt;. A patent can be used to
make money in a number of ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making and selling products or services with the patented idea&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selling the patent to another organization&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Licensing out the patent in exchange for a percentage of sales&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suing for the profits made by an organization who used the patented ideas
without your permission&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What can be patented?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While patenting restrictions vary between countries and over time,
most countries agree that a patentable idea must have all of the following
properties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mathematical formulas and pure algorithms may be amazing, but these
abstract ideas are not considered to be patentable. Which ideas are
abstract can be controversial, and so there are many examples of courts
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theiplawblog.com/2017/03/articles/patent-law/more-patent-invalidated-as-abstract-ideas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;invalidating patents after they were issued&lt;/a&gt;
due to disagreements on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man-made&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural laws and natural phenomena are also not patentable. One of the
most prominent examples of a patent portfolio being invalidated for being
natural is the case against Myriad Genetics who previously held a patent on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myriad_Genetics#Controversies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;breast cancer genes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Novel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to a publication in a research conference or journal, patentable
ideas must be significantly different from what has been published in the past.
Academics usually refer to existing publications as &amp;ldquo;related work&amp;rdquo;, while patent
attorneys refer to them as &amp;ldquo;prior art&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Useful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by far the easiest requirement to meet. All that you need to
demonstrate is that your idea successfully accomplishes some goal. That goal
need not be considered useful by a majority of people, it just needs to be
possible and legal. There are all kinds of hilarious
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oddee.com/item_96675.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patents with dubious usefulness&lt;/a&gt;
that got approved by the US patent office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-obvious&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every field of engineering and design has a certain set of common
knowledge that an expert in the field would be familiar with. If such an expert
would find an idea to be obvious or common knowledge, then that idea is
considered to be &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;. This is often a subjective judgement, so
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2014/02/01/when-is-an-invention-obvious/id=47709/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;see here&lt;/a&gt;
for further discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why should I bother patenting if I&amp;rsquo;m not the assignee?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies and universities require that you sign some form of a
Confidential Information and Inventions Assignment Agreement (CIIAA) before you
join them. The specifics of each CIIAA vary, but most force you to
give your assignee rights to your employer for all inventions that you create
while employed by them. This means that if you invent something new while
employed, only your employer can file for a patent on this invention. It is
important to remember however that your employer still needs you to perform your
duties as inventor (disclosing your invention and explaining how it works to the
attorneys), so companies and universities usually provide inventor incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incentives in industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, while you do give up your assignee rights while employed
you never give up your inventorship. This means that if you file a patent with
your organization then you will still get credit for creating the idea even if
you don&amp;rsquo;t own it. This can be a great option to get your name out there if your
organization prohibits publishing but encourages patenting. Second, companies
will often provide cash bonuses to you if your invention disclosure gets
approved for filing and/or if a patent is issued for an invention of yours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incentives in academia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond being self employed or in a startup incubator, academia is the
best work environment to build intellectual property in. A university&amp;rsquo;s goal is
to launch your career rather than make large profits, and as such they usually
give you some amount of profits from and control over your inventions. While
every research university is different, it is not uncommon for there to be a
preference to licence patents to inventors themselves if they choose to start a
company. Most universities also give a share of any profits to the inventors.
For example,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctl.cornell.edu/inventors/marketing-inventions.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cornell allocates a third of patent profits&lt;/a&gt;
to the inventor(s).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can I patent on my own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as you aren&amp;rsquo;t under a CIIAA then yes, you can patent on your own.
Fees from the patent office will be reduced because you as a person are a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/newsletter/inventors-eye/new-fees-and-micro-entity-status-take-effect-march&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;micro entity&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;,
but the cost of hiring a skilled patent attorney may be significant. The best
bet for individual inventors (and sometimes even organizations) is to first file
for a provisional patent application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should I file a provisional patent application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A provisional patent application will not be reviewed by the patent office
and will not become a patent without further applications, but it serves the all
important function of setting the filing date. A lot of work goes into building
the claims in a formal patent application, and so the provisional application
provides a way to set the date of filing before time has been spent on
developing claims. Even skilled patent attorneys will often suggest filing a
provisional patent application before continuing to the claims. Provisional
applications are also very low cost as their fees are much smaller than that of
a full application. This makes them a good option for individual or small patent
applicants who haven&amp;rsquo;t yet raised funds for a patent attorney. Keep in mind
though that a provisional application only holds power for a year unless a full
patent application has been filed in that time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When should I file?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a phrase: As Soon As Possible. You might remember being told in school
that you should date every single entry in your lab/design notebook. That was
because at the time (pre-2013) the US had a &amp;ldquo;first-to-invent&amp;rdquo; patenting system.
If someone else was to file for a patent that you had invented first (as proven
by your dated lab notebook), the other person&amp;rsquo;s patent would be invalidated.
This is no longer the case however as the US has
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_to_file_and_first_to_invent#USA_change_to_first-inventor-to-file_(FITF)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;changed to &amp;ldquo;first-inventor-to-file&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
With this in mind, if you want to patent an invention in the US or any other
&amp;ldquo;first-to-file&amp;rdquo; country you must file as soon after creating the invention as
possible to prevent others from filing before you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consideration is when to patent in relationship to publishing. In a
university your main priority as a researcher is usually to publish your work.
Some may think that this precludes you from patenting your work as well, but
this isn&amp;rsquo;t true! While some countries do prevent you from patenting after
publishing your work, the US allows a one-year grace period. A much better
strategy of course is to file a patent application before you publish.
Thankfully, most conferences and journals enforce confidentiality on
submissions, meaning that simply submitting your work for publication doesn&amp;rsquo;t
count as publication. So, if you verify that your publication venue supports
submission confidentiality then you can begin filing for your patent immediately
after finishing your submission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is my invention better protected as a patent or trade secret?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before patenting, there was very little monetary incentive to publish new
inventions. Keeping your inventions a secret ensured that no one else could use
them. If no one is sharing ideas then it is very hard for a society to progress
technologically. Patenting was proposed as a bargain with inventors: publish
exactly how your inventions work in exchange for the right to prevent others
from using those inventions for a set time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While patenting makes sense in theory, there have been
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3bxcc3SM_KA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;many issues&lt;/a&gt;
with our implementation of the system. One such issue is that it can be quite
hard to prove that someone is using your invention. Closed source software is a
perfect example of this as the actual written code is obfuscated by the
compilation process. Without the ability to prove that someone is violating your
patent, the patent is useless. Also, publishing your invention via the patenting
process could provide others with enough information to design around you. Your
patent attorney will try to make your patent&amp;rsquo;s claims as general as possible,
but clever engineers may be able to create a new system without violating your
claims that still gets the same benefit. So, before patenting your invention
consider that your competitors may either hide their use of your patent or
circumvent it through clever design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there such a thing as an international patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope! At least at the time of writing there is no such thing as an
international patent or patent office. There is however an International Patent
Cooperation Union which facilitates a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent_Cooperation_Treaty&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;single patent filing system&lt;/a&gt;
for all member countries. While no patent is granted through such an
application, it does provide a unified system for filing dates and applicants
are provided with some written opinions about the patentability of the
invention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Invention Disclosure Form (IDF)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say that after reading all of this you are convinced that you have a
great invention that would be well protected by a patent. Congratulations! If
you are in a company or university your next step is to fill out and submit an
Invention Disclosure Form. This process can be complex in and of itself, and so
I have written about it in its own separate blog post.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/idf/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;
if you&amp;rsquo;d like to read on!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguring The Imaging Pipeline For Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/iccv2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/iccv2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Advancements in deep learning have ignited an explosion of research on efficient hardware for embedded computer vision. Hardware vision acceleration, however, does not address the cost of capturing and processing the image data that feeds these algorithms. We examine the role of the image signal processing (ISP) pipeline in computer vision to identify opportunities to reduce computation and save energy. The key insight is that imaging pipelines should be designed to be configurable: to switch between a traditional photography mode and a low-power vision mode that produces lower-quality image data suitable only for computer vision. We use eight computer vision algorithms and a reversible pipeline simulation tool to study the imaging system&amp;rsquo;s impact on vision performance. For both CNN-based and classical vision algorithms, we observe that only two ISP stages, demosaicing and gamma compression, are critical for task performance. We propose a new image sensor design that can compensate for skipping these stages. The sensor design features an adjustable resolution and tunable analog-to-digital converters (ADCs). Our proposed imaging system&amp;rsquo;s vision mode disables the ISP entirely and configures the sensor to produce subsampled, lower-precision image data. This vision mode can save ~75% of the average energy of a baseline photography mode while having only a small impact on vision task accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Espresso</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/espresso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/espresso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instructions on how to use a conical burr coffee grinder and semi-automatic
espresso machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing in Docker</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker is awesome, and this talk will tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Videos with FFmpeg</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/cutting-ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/cutting-ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While building the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mbuckler/youtube-bb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;downloading and decoding
scripts&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.google.com/youtube-bb/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Youtube BoundingBoxes
dataset&lt;/a&gt; I needed to
accurately cut videos into smaller clips. Some of the annotated videos were
quite long and the annotations rarely covered the full video, so to save space
my scripts cut out and save only the annotated sections. If done incorrectly
this video cutting can cause subtle frame timing issues which I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully
understand when I started writing these scripts. If you want to avoid these
problems read below for the proper way to accurately cut videos with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ffmpeg.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a very quick review of video compression. Most modern video compression
algorithms use a technique called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_compensation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;motion
compensation&lt;/a&gt; to reduce the
size of stored video files. All frames in MPEG are stored as either Key frames
(I frames) or Predicted frames (P or B frames). Each Key frame is compressed
with some variation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JPEG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JPEG compression
codec&lt;/a&gt;, but Predicted frames are represented
as motion compensated versions of earlier frames (as in P frames) or both
earlier and later frames (as in B frames). Because these motion compensation
references take up much less space than a compressed JPEG, overall the
compressed video takes up less space. For (much) more detail you can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://users.cs.cf.ac.uk/Dave.Marshall/Multimedia/node255.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dave
Marshall&amp;rsquo;s excellent
explanation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed video compression and the different kinds of encoded
frames, we can talk about seeking. Seeking is the process used to find certain
sections of the video to either extract a frame or cut out a portion. FFmpeg has
implemented a few options for our use, but their differences in behavior and/or
usage can be easy to overlook. Here we will discuss the three methods of seeking
(and by extension cutting) video with FFmpeg, with each corresponding to a point
on the speed/accuracy tradeoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key Frame Seeking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to extract a portion of video from a larger video (with a 60
second clip starting 30 seconds in) would be the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -ss 30 -i input_vid.mp4 -t 60 -c copy output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is so fast because it uses Key frames when performing seek, and
there are far fewer Key frames than Predicted frames. It also is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/ffmpeg.html#Stream-copy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stream
copy&lt;/a&gt; meaning that the encoded data
extracted from the original video is taken directly without decoding and then
re-encoding. While this feature may be useful for some users who don&amp;rsquo;t care
about frame accuracy, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for our purposes. This is because even
though FFmpeg 2.1 enabled frame accurate Key frame seeking for frame extraction
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/Seeking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more detail here&lt;/a&gt;) this behavior is not
supported in FFmpeg 2.6 when cutting out clips of video. This means that the
start of your video will be aligned with the nearest Key frame to 30 seconds,
not the nearest frame independent of encoding format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All-Frame Seeking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slightly slower and more accurate method of video cutting would be the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -i input_vid.mp4 -ss 30 -t 60 -c copy output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you tell the difference? It is frustratingly similar to the previous
command&amp;hellip; It turns out that FFmpeg arguments are order sensitive, so choosing
the clip&amp;rsquo;s start time after the input video causes a change in behavior! This
method uses all-frame seeking, also known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/Seeking#Outputseeking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;output
seeking&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by FFmpeg users.
It is also a stream copy, but considers all frames (including Predicted frames)
when performing a seek. This means that your output clip will start with the nearest frame
to 30 seconds even if it is a predicted frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use this command and try to play your output clip, you may notice that
the clip starts frozen, or with black frames in the beginning. Did FFmpeg do
something wrong? No, that behavior is simply a result of the functionality that
we requested when we performed an all-frame seek on a stream copy. If your 30
second start happens to align with a Predicted frame, that Predicted frame will
be copied into the output clip, along with the rest of the frames in the 60
second portion. But as we already established, Predicted frames are simply
motion compensated references to previous or following Key frames. By stream
copying with all-frame seeking we have removed the reference Key frames which
came before our first frame. This is why your video player displays frozen or
black frames: the necessary data to represent the first portion of your
video isn&amp;rsquo;t included in the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full Re-Encoding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Key frame seeking causes missalignment and All-frame seeking causes broken
frames, is there another option? Yes, but some folks don&amp;rsquo;t like it. Instead of
performing a stream copy we can decode the source video, and then re-encode the
output clip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -i input_vid.mp4 -ss 30 -strict -2 -t 60 output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect for two reasons: 1) Re-encoding can cause
quality loss if done incorrectly, and 2) Re-encoding is far slower than stream
copying. While both of these two points should be considered, if you want to
copy a frame-exact section of video you have to re-encode. At least now you
know!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
