<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Buckler on Mark Buckler</title>
    <link>http://markbuckler.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mark Buckler on Mark Buckler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Mark Buckler</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Imaging Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/imaging-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/imaging-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compact talk describing the imaging pipeline from photons to pixels&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVA²: Exploiting Temporal Redundancy in Live Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/isca2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/isca2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hardware support for deep convolutional neural networks (CNNs) is critical to advanced computer vision in mobile and embedded devices. Current designs, however, accelerate generic CNNs; they do not exploit the unique characteristics of real-time vision. We propose to use the temporal redundancy in natural video to avoid unnecessary computation on most frames. A new algorithm, activation motion compensation, detects changes in the visual input and incrementally updates a previously-computed output. The technique takes inspiration from video compression and applies well-known motion estimation techniques to adapt to visual changes. We use an adaptive key frame rate to control the trade-off between efficiency and vision quality as the input changes. We implement the technique in hardware as an extension to existing state-of-the-art CNN accelerator designs. The new unit reduces the average energy per frame by 54.2%, 61.7%, and 87.6% for three CNNs with less than 1% loss in vision accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVA²: Exploiting Temporal Redundancy in Live Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/publication/isca2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 19:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/publication/isca2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patenting</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/patenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/patenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Useful information all about how to patent in both academia and industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Precision SqueezeDet</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/project/squeeze-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/project/squeeze-precision/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Invention Disclosures</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/idf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/idf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my post about
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patenting in academia and industry&lt;/a&gt;
then you know why you might want to file a patent with your university or
company. The first step to filing a patent in most organizations (after creating
the invention of course!) is filling out an Invention Disclosure Form or IDF.
These forms will be created, provided by, and reviewed by your organization&amp;rsquo;s
technology transfer office or center for technology licensing. While IDFs tend
to differ between organizations they are all intended as a way for the inventor
to communicate to the organization how a new invention works and why it is
worth patenting. If the result of the organization&amp;rsquo;s review is that the
invention should be patented then in-person meetings with patent attorneys will
be arranged to discuss in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is written as a guide for those of you who might be filling out your
first IDF. This may also be helpful to any of you who are creating the first
standard disclosure form for your organization. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some common
questions in IDFs and strategies for answering these questions well. As I say in
my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I am not a
patent attorney so please don&amp;rsquo;t take any of what I say here as legal advice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who are the inventors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases the answer to this question will be very straightforward.
Perhaps you were the only person on the project in which you created the
invention and you never discussed the invention with others. Most of the time,
however, people collaborate. If your invention was made in a project with other
people then the determination of who may or may not be considered an inventor is
a matter of discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;authorship&lt;/em&gt; on papers is generally given to people who have made
important contributions when building prototypes, performing testing, and
writing text for the paper, &lt;em&gt;inventorship&lt;/em&gt; is legally different. Patent law
defines an inventor of a patentable invention as someone who conceives of an
original, useful, and non-obvious idea. This can but does not necessarily
include students, professors, your boss, your employees, and other
collaborators. Use your best judgement and ask all collaborators who you believe
may have contributed to the idea considered in the invention disclosure. Only
after everyone agrees will the inventor list be settled. Keep in mind that who
gets to claim inventorship should not be based on charity, flattery, or spite.
Patents can and have been invalidated for an incorrect list of inventors. For
more information about this topic, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://otl.stanford.edu/documents/who_is_inv.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this helpful PDF&lt;/a&gt;
provided by Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Office of Technology Licensing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What problem does the invention solve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an invention to be useful and therefore worthy of patent protection, it
must solve some problem that exists in the world. If you are used to writing
research papers, you can think of this like the &lt;em&gt;motivation&lt;/em&gt; section in a
paper. Because the patent lawyers and other people reviewing this IDF won&amp;rsquo;t
necessarily be experts in your field make sure to include any scientific or
technical background that might be needed to understand why the invention is
useful and how it may work. This is similar to the &lt;em&gt;background&lt;/em&gt; section in a
paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What prior art are you aware of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prior art&amp;rdquo; simply refers to any patents, papers, documentation, or other
published information that you are aware of which is related to your invention.
This is similar to the &lt;em&gt;related work&lt;/em&gt; section in a research paper. If there is a
very large body of work in your field then try to focus on citing survey papers
for the general background and then limit your more specific citations to work
which is closely related. Also, do your best to list any other groups,
researchers, or companies who work in your area as it will help the attorneys
in their further prior art search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What competitors are you aware of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you list any competing products or inventions that you&amp;rsquo;re aware of.
Stress the flaws or drawbacks of each of your competitors so that you can more
easily demonstrate your advantage. If there aren&amp;rsquo;t yet any true solutions to the
problem that your invention solves then list any workarounds that you
might be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the unique features of the invention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you describe your invention&amp;rsquo;s competitive advantage and which
specific elements of your invention are novel. You can think about this like the
&lt;em&gt;contributions&lt;/em&gt; section in a paper. Try to focus both on why you are different
from the competition and why this difference results in a superior product or
method. Use your best sales skills!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the invention work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is often the most complex section of the IDF. Use pictures and visual
aids whenever possible. You could also consider including a glossary with
definitions of the jargon used throughout the IDF. Keep in mind that the readers
may not be as familiar with your subject area as you are. Technology offices try
to match inventions as closely to experts as possible, but some disciplines can
be very broad and others very specialized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there any alternative versions of the invention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In engineering we often need to make design decisions to optimize the
performance of our design or simplify the design process. Your final prototype
represents only one possible choice for each design decision. To prevent someone
from designing around your patent by making an insignificantly different choice
in their design, your patent attorney will try to make the claims of your patent
as general as possible. You can help your attorney by describing not just the
specifics of your tested prototype, but also the entire possible design space.
This can include variations that you haven&amp;rsquo;t tested, or even variations that you
have tested and have determined to be inferior to your final prototype.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How could the invention be used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you lay out all possible use cases for your invention. Ease of use is
important in evaluating the value of a potential patent. Overly onerous
inventions may not be worth the benefit they provide. If possible, provide
examples of other products or inventions with similar use cases. In a similar
spirit to listing alternative versions of your invention, get creative and try
to think of alternative uses for your invention as well. Alternative uses for
your work may make it more valuable and enable broader claims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can the use of this invention be detected?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discuss in my post on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/patenting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patenting in academia and industry&lt;/a&gt;,
part of a patent&amp;rsquo;s value is how easy it is to detect when the invention is
being used without permission. Without the ability to detect the use of the
invention, the patent can&amp;rsquo;t be enforced and is therefore useless. Your patent
attorney may be more familiar with common methods for detecting use in your
field since this isn&amp;rsquo;t a common thought for researchers, but list whatever
methods you are aware of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who might want to purchase or license the potential patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question is most relevant in academia where the assumption is not that
the patent will be used directly by your organization. Universities don&amp;rsquo;t make
products, and so a patent only has value if there is a demand for it! To answer
this question list any people or organizations who might be interested in buying
or licensing the potential patent from your organization. This can include the
most prominent companies in your field as well as any any startups you may be
aware of. Some technology offices may even begin marketing your idea before
deciding to patent your invention as a way of determining demand, so give them
as much help as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in a university and hope to launch a company using this patent,
be extremely up front about your goals. You may even want to contact the
technology licencing office before submitting an IDF to explain your intentions.
Without knowing your goals the technology licencing office may sell the patent
to an outside party without ever consulting you. Even simply marketing your
invention before it has been patented may prevent you from creating a stealth
mode startup. Make sure to communicate often and effectively with your
university&amp;rsquo;s office to avoid such an issue. Your business plan may be a part of
convincing the office to license to you instead of a large company, so prepare
your business plan as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After answering these 10 questions you will have successfully filled out your
first IDF. Congratulations!  As you can see, a great deal of the questions asked
in an IDF are similar to material that you may have already prepared for a
technical report or research publication. Feel free to directly copy and paste
from previous writing that you&amp;rsquo;ve done, and attach the original document to your
IDF for ease of reading. With any luck your organization will be interested in
filing a patent on your invention. May lots of patent filing bonuses or
licencing revenue flow your way!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patenting in Academia and Industry</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/patenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/patenting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all get excited about doing scientific or engineering research for different
reasons, but most of us seek the thrill of creating something entirely new.
In this way, research can be just as wonderful as the creative arts. Publishing
your new ideas is great for sharing information with the world, but sometimes
you want to sell your ideas too. This is where filing for a patent can be very
useful. I have some experience in this area as I have patented inventions
&lt;a href=&#34;http://patents.google.com/patent/US8289363B2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on my own&lt;/a&gt;,
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US9344099B2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;industry&lt;/a&gt;,
and most recently in academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I can&amp;rsquo;t cover the entire topic of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intellectual_property&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Intellectual Property (IP) law&lt;/a&gt;
in a single blog post, I will choose instead to answer questions that someone
might have if they were interested in patenting at a company or university. I
hope other researchers and inventors like myself will find this information
useful. Also, I am not a patent attorney, so please don&amp;rsquo;t take anything that I
say here as legal advice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is a patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you don&amp;rsquo;t already know, a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patent&lt;/a&gt; on a specific idea gives
exclusive usage rights of that idea to whoever holds the patent. In theory, this
means that the patent holder can prevent others from using the idea. The person
who creates the invention is referred to as the &lt;em&gt;inventor&lt;/em&gt;, and the person or
organization who holds the patent is the &lt;em&gt;assignee&lt;/em&gt;. A patent can be used to
make money in a number of ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making and selling products or services with the patented idea&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Selling the patent to another organization&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Licensing out the patent in exchange for a percentage of sales&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suing for the profits made by an organization who used the patented ideas
without your permission&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What can be patented?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While patenting restrictions vary between countries and over time,
most countries agree that a patentable idea must have all of the following
properties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-abstract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mathematical formulas and pure algorithms may be amazing, but these
abstract ideas are not considered to be patentable. Which ideas are
abstract can be controversial, and so there are many examples of courts
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theiplawblog.com/2017/03/articles/patent-law/more-patent-invalidated-as-abstract-ideas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;invalidating patents after they were issued&lt;/a&gt;
due to disagreements on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man-made&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural laws and natural phenomena are also not patentable. One of the
most prominent examples of a patent portfolio being invalidated for being
natural is the case against Myriad Genetics who previously held a patent on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myriad_Genetics#Controversies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;breast cancer genes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Novel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to a publication in a research conference or journal, patentable
ideas must be significantly different from what has been published in the past.
Academics usually refer to existing publications as &amp;ldquo;related work&amp;rdquo;, while patent
attorneys refer to them as &amp;ldquo;prior art&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Useful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by far the easiest requirement to meet. All that you need to
demonstrate is that your idea successfully accomplishes some goal. That goal
need not be considered useful by a majority of people, it just needs to be
possible and legal. There are all kinds of hilarious
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oddee.com/item_96675.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;patents with dubious usefulness&lt;/a&gt;
that got approved by the US patent office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-obvious&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every field of engineering and design has a certain set of common
knowledge that an expert in the field would be familiar with. If such an expert
would find an idea to be obvious or common knowledge, then that idea is
considered to be &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;. This is often a subjective judgement, so
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipwatchdog.com/2014/02/01/when-is-an-invention-obvious/id=47709/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;see here&lt;/a&gt;
for further discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why should I bother patenting if I&amp;rsquo;m not the assignee?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies and universities require that you sign some form of a
Confidential Information and Inventions Assignment Agreement (CIIAA) before you
join them. The specifics of each CIIAA vary, but most force you to
give your assignee rights to your employer for all inventions that you create
while employed by them. This means that if you invent something new while
employed, only your employer can file for a patent on this invention. It is
important to remember however that your employer still needs you to perform your
duties as inventor (disclosing your invention and explaining how it works to the
attorneys), so companies and universities usually provide inventor incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incentives in industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, while you do give up your assignee rights while employed
you never give up your inventorship. This means that if you file a patent with
your organization then you will still get credit for creating the idea even if
you don&amp;rsquo;t own it. This can be a great option to get your name out there if your
organization prohibits publishing but encourages patenting. Second, companies
will often provide cash bonuses to you if your invention disclosure gets
approved for filing and/or if a patent is issued for an invention of yours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incentives in academia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond being self employed or in a startup incubator, academia is the
best work environment to build intellectual property in. A university&amp;rsquo;s goal is
to launch your career rather than make large profits, and as such they usually
give you some amount of profits from and control over your inventions. While
every research university is different, it is not uncommon for there to be a
preference to licence patents to inventors themselves if they choose to start a
company. Most universities also give a share of any profits to the inventors.
For example,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctl.cornell.edu/inventors/marketing-inventions.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cornell allocates a third of patent profits&lt;/a&gt;
to the inventor(s).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can I patent on my own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as you aren&amp;rsquo;t under a CIIAA then yes, you can patent on your own.
Fees from the patent office will be reduced because you as a person are a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/newsletter/inventors-eye/new-fees-and-micro-entity-status-take-effect-march&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;micro entity&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;,
but the cost of hiring a skilled patent attorney may be significant. The best
bet for individual inventors (and sometimes even organizations) is to first file
for a provisional patent application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should I file a provisional patent application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A provisional patent application will not be reviewed by the patent office
and will not become a patent without further applications, but it serves the all
important function of setting the filing date. A lot of work goes into building
the claims in a formal patent application, and so the provisional application
provides a way to set the date of filing before time has been spent on
developing claims. Even skilled patent attorneys will often suggest filing a
provisional patent application before continuing to the claims. Provisional
applications are also very low cost as their fees are much smaller than that of
a full application. This makes them a good option for individual or small patent
applicants who haven&amp;rsquo;t yet raised funds for a patent attorney. Keep in mind
though that a provisional application only holds power for a year unless a full
patent application has been filed in that time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When should I file?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a phrase: As Soon As Possible. You might remember being told in school
that you should date every single entry in your lab/design notebook. That was
because at the time (pre-2013) the US had a &amp;ldquo;first-to-invent&amp;rdquo; patenting system.
If someone else was to file for a patent that you had invented first (as proven
by your dated lab notebook), the other person&amp;rsquo;s patent would be invalidated.
This is no longer the case however as the US has
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_to_file_and_first_to_invent#USA_change_to_first-inventor-to-file_(FITF)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;changed to &amp;ldquo;first-inventor-to-file&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.
With this in mind, if you want to patent an invention in the US or any other
&amp;ldquo;first-to-file&amp;rdquo; country you must file as soon after creating the invention as
possible to prevent others from filing before you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consideration is when to patent in relationship to publishing. In a
university your main priority as a researcher is usually to publish your work.
Some may think that this precludes you from patenting your work as well, but
this isn&amp;rsquo;t true! While some countries do prevent you from patenting after
publishing your work, the US allows a one-year grace period. A much better
strategy of course is to file a patent application before you publish.
Thankfully, most conferences and journals enforce confidentiality on
submissions, meaning that simply submitting your work for publication doesn&amp;rsquo;t
count as publication. So, if you verify that your publication venue supports
submission confidentiality then you can begin filing for your patent immediately
after finishing your submission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is my invention better protected as a patent or trade secret?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before patenting, there was very little monetary incentive to publish new
inventions. Keeping your inventions a secret ensured that no one else could use
them. If no one is sharing ideas then it is very hard for a society to progress
technologically. Patenting was proposed as a bargain with inventors: publish
exactly how your inventions work in exchange for the right to prevent others
from using those inventions for a set time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While patenting makes sense in theory, there have been
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3bxcc3SM_KA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;many issues&lt;/a&gt;
with our implementation of the system. One such issue is that it can be quite
hard to prove that someone is using your invention. Closed source software is a
perfect example of this as the actual written code is obfuscated by the
compilation process. Without the ability to prove that someone is violating your
patent, the patent is useless. Also, publishing your invention via the patenting
process could provide others with enough information to design around you. Your
patent attorney will try to make your patent&amp;rsquo;s claims as general as possible,
but clever engineers may be able to create a new system without violating your
claims that still gets the same benefit. So, before patenting your invention
consider that your competitors may either hide their use of your patent or
circumvent it through clever design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there such a thing as an international patent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope! At least at the time of writing there is no such thing as an
international patent or patent office. There is however an International Patent
Cooperation Union which facilitates a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patent_Cooperation_Treaty&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;single patent filing system&lt;/a&gt;
for all member countries. While no patent is granted through such an
application, it does provide a unified system for filing dates and applicants
are provided with some written opinions about the patentability of the
invention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Invention Disclosure Form (IDF)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say that after reading all of this you are convinced that you have a
great invention that would be well protected by a patent. Congratulations! If
you are in a company or university your next step is to fill out and submit an
Invention Disclosure Form. This process can be complex in and of itself, and so
I have written about it in its own separate blog post.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markbuckler.com/post/idf/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;
if you&amp;rsquo;d like to read on!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguring The Imaging Pipeline For Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/iccv2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/iccv2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Advancements in deep learning have ignited an explosion of research on efficient hardware for embedded computer vision. Hardware vision acceleration, however, does not address the cost of capturing and processing the image data that feeds these algorithms. We examine the role of the image signal processing (ISP) pipeline in computer vision to identify opportunities to reduce computation and save energy. The key insight is that imaging pipelines should be designed to be configurable: to switch between a traditional photography mode and a low-power vision mode that produces lower-quality image data suitable only for computer vision. We use eight computer vision algorithms and a reversible pipeline simulation tool to study the imaging system&amp;rsquo;s impact on vision performance. For both CNN-based and classical vision algorithms, we observe that only two ISP stages, demosaicing and gamma compression, are critical for task performance. We propose a new image sensor design that can compensate for skipping these stages. The sensor design features an adjustable resolution and tunable analog-to-digital converters (ADCs). Our proposed imaging system&amp;rsquo;s vision mode disables the ISP entirely and configures the sensor to produce subsampled, lower-precision image data. This vision mode can save ~75% of the average energy of a baseline photography mode while having only a small impact on vision task accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Espresso</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/espresso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/espresso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instructions on how to use a conical burr coffee grinder and semi-automatic
espresso machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing in Docker</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/talk/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/talk/docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker is awesome, and this talk will tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Videos with FFmpeg</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/cutting-ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/cutting-ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While building the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mbuckler/youtube-bb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;downloading and decoding
scripts&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.google.com/youtube-bb/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Youtube BoundingBoxes
dataset&lt;/a&gt; I needed to
accurately cut videos into smaller clips. Some of the annotated videos were
quite long and the annotations rarely covered the full video, so to save space
my scripts cut out and save only the annotated sections. If done incorrectly
this video cutting can cause subtle frame timing issues which I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully
understand when I started writing these scripts. If you want to avoid these
problems read below for the proper way to accurately cut videos with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ffmpeg.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a very quick review of video compression. Most modern video compression
algorithms use a technique called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_compensation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;motion
compensation&lt;/a&gt; to reduce the
size of stored video files. All frames in MPEG are stored as either Key frames
(I frames) or Predicted frames (P or B frames). Each Key frame is compressed
with some variation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JPEG&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JPEG compression
codec&lt;/a&gt;, but Predicted frames are represented
as motion compensated versions of earlier frames (as in P frames) or both
earlier and later frames (as in B frames). Because these motion compensation
references take up much less space than a compressed JPEG, overall the
compressed video takes up less space. For (much) more detail you can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://users.cs.cf.ac.uk/Dave.Marshall/Multimedia/node255.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dave
Marshall&amp;rsquo;s excellent
explanation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed video compression and the different kinds of encoded
frames, we can talk about seeking. Seeking is the process used to find certain
sections of the video to either extract a frame or cut out a portion. FFmpeg has
implemented a few options for our use, but their differences in behavior and/or
usage can be easy to overlook. Here we will discuss the three methods of seeking
(and by extension cutting) video with FFmpeg, with each corresponding to a point
on the speed/accuracy tradeoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key Frame Seeking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to extract a portion of video from a larger video (with a 60
second clip starting 30 seconds in) would be the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -ss 30 -i input_vid.mp4 -t 60 -c copy output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is so fast because it uses Key frames when performing seek, and
there are far fewer Key frames than Predicted frames. It also is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/ffmpeg.html#Stream-copy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;stream
copy&lt;/a&gt; meaning that the encoded data
extracted from the original video is taken directly without decoding and then
re-encoding. While this feature may be useful for some users who don&amp;rsquo;t care
about frame accuracy, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for our purposes. This is because even
though FFmpeg 2.1 enabled frame accurate Key frame seeking for frame extraction
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/Seeking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more detail here&lt;/a&gt;) this behavior is not
supported in FFmpeg 2.6 when cutting out clips of video. This means that the
start of your video will be aligned with the nearest Key frame to 30 seconds,
not the nearest frame independent of encoding format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All-Frame Seeking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slightly slower and more accurate method of video cutting would be the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -i input_vid.mp4 -ss 30 -t 60 -c copy output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you tell the difference? It is frustratingly similar to the previous
command&amp;hellip; It turns out that FFmpeg arguments are order sensitive, so choosing
the clip&amp;rsquo;s start time after the input video causes a change in behavior! This
method uses all-frame seeking, also known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.ffmpeg.org/wiki/Seeking#Outputseeking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;output
seeking&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by FFmpeg users.
It is also a stream copy, but considers all frames (including Predicted frames)
when performing a seek. This means that your output clip will start with the nearest frame
to 30 seconds even if it is a predicted frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use this command and try to play your output clip, you may notice that
the clip starts frozen, or with black frames in the beginning. Did FFmpeg do
something wrong? No, that behavior is simply a result of the functionality that
we requested when we performed an all-frame seek on a stream copy. If your 30
second start happens to align with a Predicted frame, that Predicted frame will
be copied into the output clip, along with the rest of the frames in the 60
second portion. But as we already established, Predicted frames are simply
motion compensated references to previous or following Key frames. By stream
copying with all-frame seeking we have removed the reference Key frames which
came before our first frame. This is why your video player displays frozen or
black frames: the necessary data to represent the first portion of your
video isn&amp;rsquo;t included in the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full Re-Encoding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Key frame seeking causes missalignment and All-frame seeking causes broken
frames, is there another option? Yes, but some folks don&amp;rsquo;t like it. Instead of
performing a stream copy we can decode the source video, and then re-encode the
output clip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg -i input_vid.mp4 -ss 30 -strict -2 -t 60 output_clip.mp4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect for two reasons: 1) Re-encoding can cause
quality loss if done incorrectly, and 2) Re-encoding is far slower than stream
copying. While both of these two points should be considered, if you want to
copy a frame-exact section of video you have to re-encode. At least now you
know!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approximate Vision Pipeline</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/project/approx-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/project/approx-vision/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Old Electronic Music Blog</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/post/quoth_the_raver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 16:25:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/post/quoth_the_raver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2010 I started a blog dedicated to electronic music called Quoth
the Raver (a play on Quoth the Raven). It was a huge amount of fun
sharing the music I found with everyone on the site, and it inspired me
to get even more familiar with the various genres, artists, and labels.
These days electronic music (also known as EDM) has exploded in
popularity, so the novelty of sharing new artists has worn off to a
certain extent. For this reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated the blog in quite a
long time, but I did recently go through to fix up some broken components
for archiving the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone is curious to see what I was listening to and raving about
back then feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://quoththeraverarchive.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;check out the
website!&lt;/a&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re more
interested in what I&amp;rsquo;m listening to these days, go ahead and check out
what I love on &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/quoththeraver&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://markbuckler.com/img/quoth_the_raver.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Quoth the Raver&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguring the Imaging Pipeline for Computer Vision</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/publication/iccv2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 19:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/publication/iccv2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube BoundingBox Dataset Downloader</title>
      <link>http://markbuckler.com/project/youtube-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markbuckler.com/project/youtube-bb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
